{
    "id": "18_Health_230",
    "claim": "It is cheap and its effect is immediate and powerful, but also lethal. Fentanyl, an opioid to treat cancer-related pain, among other diseases, is one of the drugs that is currently of greatest concern to authorities in the United States, where the number of overdose deaths associated with the drug has skyrocketed. It's #NUMBER* times more powerful than heroin and even #NUMBER* more than morphine. 'Fentanyl-related overdoses are increasing alarmingly and pose a significant threat to public safety and health ', said the U.S. Drug Enforcement Agency a year ago. USA. (DEA), in an alert message. According to the latest DEA Drug Report, there have been  fentanyl-related deaths in the United States since the end of  at the end of , the latest available data. The trend, according to experts, has remained upwards. The DEA believes, however, that deaths are many more, as the drug is behind many of the heroin overdoses, the drug that continues to cause more deaths: more than  in . 'Epidemic 'Fentanyl is related to the 'heroin epidemic 'that the United States authorities say is suffering from. President Barack Obama announced Tuesday new funds to stop the wave of deaths caused by the use of heroin and opiate analgesics. 'I don't think the public really realizes the scope of the problem ', Obama said Tuesday at a summit against drug and heroin abuse. The number of deaths from heroin overdose increased in the U.S. USA. % between  and . Local data reflect the rising threat of fentanyl in the United States. The state of New Hampshire reported four fentanyl deaths in two months. In New Jersey there were #NUMBER* in just six months on #NUMBER*. In  months, deaths were reported in Pennsylvania. The number of deaths is linked to the number of drugs seized. In , authorities reported  seizures of fentanyl by  of . From January  to September , the latest data provided by the DEA, the number was increased to . Here are some questions to understand the phenomenon. What is fentanyl?It is a narcotic used as an analgesic and anaesthetic. The most powerful opioid available for medical use. Its power and immediate effects are behind the addiction it generates. Heroin, by comparison, provides a more durable but less immediate feeling, making it easier to treat by emergency medical services in case of overdose. That even means that many of those who died from overdose are found with the syringe in their arm. Fentanyl is injected, but also applied in patches and taken in tablets. The one that occurs in clandestine laboratories, unlike the pharmacist, is the one that is behind the most deaths, since it is mixed with heroin. It's even sold as a substitute because it's a very similar white powder and it's also similar to cocaine. But fentanyl is much more potent. Users, often without knowing what it is, consume it as heroin, so with the same amount it is much more lethal. In addition, mixing with cocaine and heroin further increases its effects, according to experts. On the street it receives other names, such as'China White'. Where does it come from?The DEA says that fentanyl comes mainly from Mexico, where the authorities have dismantled several laboratories. Although the threat is increasing, fentanyl is not a new drug. Already between  and , more than  deaths were attributed to the drug, many of them in cities such as Chicago, Detroit and Philadelphia. The substances related to these deaths were tracked and DEA reached a laboratory in Mexico. When it was dismantled, the substance almost disappeared from the market. According to U.S. authorities, the drug produced in Mexico crosses the southwestern border and reaches California and Arizona, from where it is redistributed to the main heroin markets, especially on the east coast. Cartels such as Sinaloa, according to what emerges from DEA research, add doses of fentanyl or derivatives to Mexican heroin, resulting in increased addiction and more likely overdose. Its use is part of the so-called 'epidemic 'of heroin and opiate use throughout the country. It's not just about fentanyl anymore, it's about its derivatives. The current outbreak is much wider geographically and involves a greater typology of people, according to the authorities. According to an intermediary quoted by The New York Times, ten grams of fentanyl cost USUSD and are sold to the final consumer for USUSD, allowing them to earn USUSD per week. 'It is cheaper and the effect is better ', one consumer told New York newspaper. 'It's the best I've ever taken ', another told Macleans magazine in Canada, where also the use of this drug and its consequences are on the rise. Another factor to take into account is addiction to legal opiates. According to the U.S. Centers for Disease Control (CDC), people die in the U.S. USA. every day for an overdose of painkillers prescribed by doctors. In , millions of opium-derived recipes were made in the country . How to stop it? 'Fentanyl will remain a threat as long as current clandestine production continues ', says the DEA in its report on drugs of . Experts believe that the lack of experience of clandestine laboratories that have joined the production of fentanyl is behind many deaths. These laboratories are the first to be interested in ensuring that their product does not lead to further deaths. For the DEA, the danger, they insist, is that consumers don't know that they're taking it. 'It will be consumed mostly unconsciously mixed with heroin and other drugs ', alerts the DEA. I'm sorry.",
    "source": "www.bbc.com",
    "date": "29/03/2016",
    "veracity": 1,
    "claims": [
        {
            "claim": "The number of deaths from heroin overdose fentanyl The number of deaths from heroin overdose powerful, but the U.S. USA .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did bbc report on 29/03/2016?",
                    "answer": "The number of deaths from heroin overdose fentanyl"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many deaths from heroin overdose are there in the United States?",
                    "score": 0.8731,
                    "answers": "on 29/03/2016|prep\tthat|mark\tThe|det\theroin|compound\tThe|det\theroin|compound\tthat The number of deaths from heroin overdose fentanyl The number of deaths from heroin overdose powerful , but the U.S. USA|ccomp\tbut|cc\tthe|det\tthe U.S. USA|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the number of deaths from heroin overdose?",
                    "score": 0.8725,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 29/03/2016 that The number of deaths from heroin overdose fentanyl The number of deaths from heroin overdose powerful , but the U.S. USA|ROOT\tthat The number of deaths from heroin overdose fentanyl|dep\tof deaths from heroin overdose fentanyl|prep\tdeaths from heroin overdose fentanyl|pobj\tfrom heroin overdose fentanyl|prep\tthat The number of deaths from heroin overdose fentanyl The number of deaths from heroin overdose|nsubj\tof deaths from heroin overdose|prep\tdeaths from heroin overdose|pobj\tfrom heroin overdose|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "It fentanyl It fentanyl It the U.S. USA drugs The New York Times of greatest concern fentanyl authorities in the United States the final consumer of overdose deaths associated with It has skyrocketed.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What newspaper reported that it fentanyl was of greatest concern fentanyl authorities in the United States?",
                    "answer": "The New York Times"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What type of drugs is fentanyl?",
                    "score": 0.8779,
                    "answers": "It fentanyl It the U.S. USA drugs The New York Times|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many overdose deaths are linked to fentanyl?",
                    "score": 0.8707,
                    "answers": "fentanyl authorities in the United States the final consumer of overdose deaths associated with It|nsubj\tthe final consumer of overdose deaths associated with It|appos\tof overdose deaths associated with It|prep\toverdose deaths associated with It|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between fentanyl and overdose deaths?",
                    "score": 0.8481,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 29/03/2016 that It fentanyl It fentanyl It the U.S. USA drugs The New York Times of greatest concern fentanyl authorities in the United States the final consumer of overdose deaths associated with It has skyrocketed|ROOT\ton 29/03/2016|prep\tthat|mark\tfentanyl|appos\tfentanyl|appos\tIt|dep\tthe|det\tU.S.|compound\tthe U.S. USA|compound\tThe|det\tNew|compound\tNew York|compound\tof greatest concern|prep\tgreatest|amod\tgreatest concern|pobj\tfentanyl|compound\tin the United States|prep\tthe|det\tUnited|compound\tthe|det\tfinal|amod\tassociated with It|acl\twith It|prep\tIt|pobj\thas|aux"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the amount of overdose deaths associated with it?",
                    "score": 0.8359,
                    "answers": "that It fentanyl It fentanyl It the U.S. USA drugs The New York Times of greatest concern fentanyl authorities in the United States the final consumer of overdose deaths associated with It has skyrocketed|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is fentanyl?",
                    "score": 0.832,
                    "answers": "It fentanyl It fentanyl It the U.S. USA drugs The New York Times of greatest concern|dep\tIt fentanyl It the U.S. USA drugs|nmod\tIt the U.S. USA drugs|appos"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "It 's #from?The DEA more powerful fentanyl heroin The New York Times Mexico, where the authorities have dismantled several laboratories .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the name of the DEA's more powerful fentanyl heroin?",
                    "answer": "It"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How powerful is the heroin The New York Times Mexico?",
                    "score": 0.8768,
                    "answers": "more powerful|amod\tmore powerful fentanyl heroin|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Where did the DEA dismantled several laboratories?",
                    "score": 0.8723,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tNew|compound\t,|punct"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of how powerful fentanyl heroin is?",
                    "score": 0.8631,
                    "answers": "DEA more powerful fentanyl heroin|punct"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Where did the authorities dismantled several laboratories?",
                    "score": 0.8575,
                    "answers": "where the authorities have dismantled several laboratories|relcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the drug that has been dismantled in Mexico?",
                    "score": 0.7581,
                    "answers": "The New York Times Mexico , where the authorities have dismantled several laboratories|npadvmod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Mexico, where the authorities have dismantled several laboratories alarmingly and pose a significant fentanyl fentanyl public fentanyl and health ', said the U.S. Drug Enforcement Agency more than  deaths the U.S. Drug Enforcement Agency a year ago.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did the U.S. Drug Enforcement Agency say about Mexico?",
                    "answer": "public fentanyl and health"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What drugs are being dismantled in Mexico?",
                    "score": 0.7609,
                    "answers": "Mexico , the authorities have dismantled several laboratories alarmingly and where pose a significant fentanyl fentanyl public fentanyl and health|nsubj\tthe authorities have dismantled several laboratories alarmingly and where pose a significant fentanyl fentanyl public fentanyl and health|relcl\tthat Mexico , the authorities have dismantled several laboratories alarmingly and where pose a significant fentanyl fentanyl public fentanyl and health ' , said the U.S. Drug Enforcement Agency more than|ccomp\tDrug|compound\tDrug|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many deaths from the U.S. Drug Enforcement Agency a year ago occurred in Mexico?",
                    "score": 0.7495,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many labs have been dismantled in Mexico?",
                    "score": 0.7267,
                    "answers": "several laboratories|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many deaths have occurred in the US Drug Enforcement Agency in the last year?",
                    "score": 0.7216,
                    "answers": "that|mark\t,|punct\twhere|advmod\tthe|det\tseveral|amod\tand|cc\ta|det\tand|cc\t'|punct\t,|punct\tthe|det\tthe|det\ta|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the amount of fentanyl and human activity in Mexico?",
                    "score": 0.7215,
                    "answers": "a significant fentanyl fentanyl public fentanyl and health|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "fentanyl .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did bbc.com report that fentanyl was being used?",
                    "answer": "29/03/2016"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the fentanyl?",
                    "score": 0.8342,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 29/03/2016 that fentanyl|ROOT\ton 29/03/2016|prep\tthat|mark\tthat fentanyl|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "fentanyl the U.S. Drug Enforcement Agency , in an more than  deaths message.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who was responsible for the deaths of fentanyl?",
                    "answer": "the U.S. Drug Enforcement Agency"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many deaths did fentanyl cause in 2016?",
                    "score": 0.8719,
                    "answers": "on 29/03/2016|prep\tthat|mark\tfentanyl|dep\tthe|det\tU.S.|compound\tDrug|compound\tDrug Enforcement|compound\t,|punct\tan|det\tthan|prep\t |dep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many deaths were there from fentanyl in 2016?",
                    "score": 0.8691,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 29/03/2016 that fentanyl the U.S. Drug Enforcement Agency , in an more than   deaths message|ROOT\tdeaths|nmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many deaths have been linked to fentanyl in 2016?",
                    "score": 0.8639,
                    "answers": "in an more than|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "According to the latest fentanyl?It , there have been  fentanylthe U.S. USA. in the United States since a laboratory in Mexico of , the fentanyl?It available fentanyl .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the fentanyl available in the U.S.?",
                    "answer": "fentanyl?It"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Where was fentanyl found in the U.S.?",
                    "answer": "a laboratory in Mexico of"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What type of fentanyl is available in the US?",
                    "score": 0.8216,
                    "answers": "the fentanyl?It available fentanyl|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the most available fentanyl in the US?",
                    "score": 0.8155,
                    "answers": "to the latest fentanyl?It|prep\tthe latest fentanyl?It|pobj\ta laboratory in Mexico of , the fentanyl?It available fentanyl|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many cases of fentanyl are available in the US per day?",
                    "score": 0.8103,
                    "answers": "since a laboratory in Mexico of , the fentanyl?It available fentanyl|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "fentanyl , according to experts, the U.S. USA. upwards.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What drug did the bbc report was used in the U.S.?",
                    "answer": "fentanyl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What drug did the bbc report was used in the U.S.?",
                    "answer": "fentanyl"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the amount of fentanyl in the USA?",
                    "score": 0.8116,
                    "answers": "according to experts|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between fentanyl and the US?",
                    "score": 0.7931,
                    "answers": "upwards|ROOT"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "the U.S. Drug Enforcement Agency fentanyl , howeverfentanyl more, as It is behind many of the heroin overdosesthe DEA the the DEA that continues to cause more deaths: more than  in .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What drug is used by the DEA for heroin overdoses?",
                    "answer": "fentanyl"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many deaths are attributed to heroin overdosesthe DEA?",
                    "score": 0.8192,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 29/03/2016 that the U.S. Drug Enforcement Agency fentanyl , howeverfentanyl more , as It is behind many of the heroin overdosesthe DEA the the DEA that continues to cause more deaths : more than   in|ROOT\tthat the U.S. Drug Enforcement Agency fentanyl , howeverfentanyl more ,|npadvmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the death rate of heroin overdosesthe DEA?",
                    "score": 0.7877,
                    "answers": "that continues to cause more deaths : more than|ccomp\tto cause more deaths : more than|xcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between heroin and opiods?",
                    "score": 0.7753,
                    "answers": "heroin|compound"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "many of those who died from overdose clandestine laboratories that have joined the production of fentanyl say is suffering clandestine laboratories that have joined the production of fentanyl .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did www.bbc.com report on 29/03/2016",
                    "answer": "many of those who died from overdose clandestine laboratories that have joined the production of fentanyl"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many people have died from overdose in the production of fentanyl?",
                    "score": 0.8216,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 29/03/2016 that many of those who died from overdose clandestine laboratories that have joined the production of fentanyl say is suffering clandestine laboratories that have joined the production of fentanyl|ROOT\ton 29/03/2016|prep\tthat|mark\tmany of those who died from overdose clandestine laboratories that have joined the production of fentanyl|nsubj\tof those who died from overdose clandestine laboratories that have joined the production of fentanyl|prep\tthose who died from overdose clandestine laboratories that have joined the production of fentanyl|pobj\twho|nsubj\twho died from overdose clandestine laboratories that have joined the production of fentanyl|relcl\tfrom overdose clandestine laboratories that have joined the production of fentanyl|prep\tclandestine|amod\tthat|nsubj\thave|aux\tthat have joined the production of fentanyl|relcl\tthe|det\tof fentanyl|prep\tfentanyl|pobj\tthat many of those who died from overdose clandestine laboratories that have joined the production of fentanyl say is suffering clandestine laboratories that have joined the production of fentanyl|ccomp\tis|aux\tis suffering clandestine laboratories that have joined the production of fentanyl|ccomp\tclandestine|amod\tclandestine laboratories that have joined the production of fentanyl|dobj\tthat|nsubj\thave|aux\tthat have joined the production of fentanyl|relcl\tthe|det\tof fentanyl|prep\tfentanyl|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "clandestine laboratories that have joined the production of fentanyl fentanyl President Barack Obama announced The one that occurs in clandestine laboratories, unlike the pharmacist clandestine laboratories that have joined the production of fentanyl The one that occurs in clandestine laboratories, unlike the pharmacist the wave of deaths caused by the use of heroin and opiate analgesics the DEA the wave of deaths caused by the use of heroin and opiate analgesics .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who is responsible for the wave of deaths caused by the use of heroin and opiate analgesics?",
                    "answer": "DEA"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many deaths were caused by the use of heroin and opiate opiate analgesics?",
                    "score": 0.8048,
                    "answers": "President Barack Obama announced|dep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the names of the clandestine labs that produce fentanyl?",
                    "score": 0.7951,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 29/03/2016 that clandestine laboratories that have joined the production of fentanyl fentanyl President Barack Obama announced|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the production of fentanyl in clandestine labs?",
                    "score": 0.7929,
                    "answers": "in clandestine laboratories|prep\tin clandestine laboratories|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "'the DEA n't think the public consumers realizes the scope of the wave of deaths caused by the use of heroin and opiate analgesics ', President Barack Obama said Tuesday The one that occurs in clandestine laboratories, unlike the pharmacist fentanyl against drug and heroin abuse.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did the DEA say the public didn't realize the extent of the wave of deaths caused by the use of?",
                    "answer": "heroin and opiate analgesics"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many deaths have been caused by the use of opiate analgesics?",
                    "score": 0.8452,
                    "answers": "of the wave of deaths caused by the use of heroin and opiate analgesics|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many deaths are attributed to opiate analgesics?",
                    "score": 0.824,
                    "answers": "public|amod\tPresident|compound\tBarack|compound\twww.bbc.com reported on 29/03/2016 that ' the DEA n't think the public consumers realizes the scope of the wave of deaths caused by the use of heroin and opiate analgesics ' , President Barack Obama said Tuesday The one that occurs in clandestine laboratories , unlike the pharmacist fentanyl against drug and heroin abuse|ROOT\tThe|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are opiate analgesics?",
                    "score": 0.8008,
                    "answers": "opiate analgesics|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the use of heroin and opiate analgesics?",
                    "score": 0.7974,
                    "answers": "the use of heroin and opiate analgesics|pobj\tThe one that occurs in clandestine laboratories , unlike the pharmacist fentanyl against drug and heroin abuse|dep\tin clandestine laboratories|prep\tunlike the pharmacist fentanyl against drug and heroin abuse|appos\tdrug and heroin|nmod\theroin|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between opiate and heroin abuse?",
                    "score": 0.7467,
                    "answers": "the pharmacist|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The number of deaths from heroin overdose increased in the U.S. USA.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that the number of deaths from heroin overdose increased in the U.S.?",
                    "answer": "www.bbc.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the number of deaths from heroin overdose in the United States?",
                    "score": 0.8584,
                    "answers": "on 29/03/2016|prep\tthat|mark\tThe|det\tThe number of deaths from heroin overdose|nsubj\tof deaths from heroin overdose|prep\tdeaths from heroin overdose|pobj\theroin|compound\tthat The number of deaths from heroin overdose increased in the U.S. USA|ccomp\tin the U.S. USA|prep\tthe|det\tthe U.S. USA|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "% between  and .",
            "question_answers": [],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the percentage between 2015 and 2016?",
                    "score": 0.7824,
                    "answers": "on 29/03/2016|prep\tthat|mark\tthat % between|dep\tbetween|prep\t  and|dep\tand|cc"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between thebbc.com and the website?",
                    "score": 0.5982,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Local data reflect the rising threat of fentanyl in the United States.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What drug is a rising threat in the United States?",
                    "answer": "fentanyl"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the current threat of fentanyl in the United States?",
                    "score": 0.8441,
                    "answers": "on 29/03/2016|prep\tLocal|amod\tLocal data|nsubj\trising|amod\tUnited|compound"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The state of New Hampshire reported four fentanyl deaths in two months.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How many fentanyl deaths did the state of New Hampshire report in two months?",
                    "answer": "four"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many deaths occurred in New Hampshire in the first two months of 2016?",
                    "score": 0.8619,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 29/03/2016 that The state of New Hampshire reported four fentanyl deaths in two months|ROOT\ton 29/03/2016|prep\tthat|mark\tThe|det\tThe state of New Hampshire|nsubj\tof New Hampshire|prep\tNew|compound\tthat The state of New Hampshire reported four fentanyl deaths in two months|ccomp\tfentanyl|compound\tfour fentanyl deaths in two months|dobj\tin two months|prep\ttwo|nummod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "In New Jersey there were #NUMBER* in just six months on #NUMBER*.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How long did it take for #NUMBER* to increase in New Jersey?",
                    "answer": "six months"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many NUMBERS were there in New Jersey in just six months in 2016?",
                    "score": 0.7444,
                    "answers": "that In New Jersey there were # NUMBER * in just six months on # NUMBER *|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "In  months, deaths were reported in Pennsylvania.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did www.bbc.com report that deaths were reported in Pennsylvania?",
                    "answer": "29/03/2016"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many deaths were reported in Pennsylvania in 2016?",
                    "score": 0.9001,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 29/03/2016 that In   months , deaths were reported in Pennsylvania|ROOT\ton 29/03/2016|prep\tthat|mark\tIn   months|prep\t  months|dep\t,|punct\tdeaths|nsubjpass\twere|auxpass\tthat In   months , deaths were reported in Pennsylvania|ccomp\tin Pennsylvania|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The number of deaths is linked to the number of drugs seized.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did www.bbc.com report that the number of deaths were linked to the number of drugs seized?",
                    "answer": "29/03/2016"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many deaths are linked to drugs seized each year?",
                    "score": 0.9162,
                    "answers": "The number of deaths|nsubjpass\tof deaths|prep\tdeaths|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many drugs were seized in 2016?",
                    "score": 0.9002,
                    "answers": "to the number of drugs seized|prep\tthe number of drugs seized|pobj\tdrugs|pobj\tseized|acl"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "In , authorities reported  seizures of fentanyl by  of .",
            "question_answers": [],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the seizures of fentanyl by authorities?",
                    "score": 0.8197,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\ton 29/03/2016|prep\tthat|mark\tIn|prep\t,|punct\tfentanyl|pobj\tby|prep\t  of|dep\tof|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "From January  to September , the latest data provided by the DEA, the number was increased to .",
            "question_answers": [],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the number of deaths from January to September in 2016?",
                    "score": 0.8284,
                    "answers": "From January  |dep\tthat From January   to September , the latest data provided by the DEA , the number was increased to|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Here are some questions to understand the phenomenon.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did bbc.com report on the phenomenon?",
                    "answer": "29/03/2016"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How can we understand the phenomena?",
                    "score": 0.8744,
                    "answers": "to understand the phenomenon|relcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are some questions to understand the phenomena?",
                    "score": 0.8127,
                    "answers": "Here|advmod\tsome|det\tto|aux"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the origin of the phenomena?",
                    "score": 0.7922,
                    "answers": "on 29/03/2016|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the study of the phenomenon?",
                    "score": 0.7839,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tthe|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the phenomenon?",
                    "score": 0.7832,
                    "answers": "the phenomenon|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "What is fentanyl?It is a narcotic used as an analgesic and anaesthetic.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is fentanyl?",
                    "answer": "fentanyl?It is a narcotic used as an analgesic and anaesthetic"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What type of anaesthetic is fentanyl?",
                    "score": 0.8904,
                    "answers": "anaesthetic|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How is fentanyl used as an analgesic and anaesthetic?",
                    "score": 0.8839,
                    "answers": "as an analgesic and anaesthetic|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the uses of fentanyl?",
                    "score": 0.853,
                    "answers": "used as an analgesic and anaesthetic|acl\tan analgesic and anaesthetic|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the use of fentanyl?",
                    "score": 0.8355,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is fentanyl?",
                    "score": 0.83,
                    "answers": "fentanyl?It|attr\tis a narcotic used as an analgesic and anaesthetic|ccomp\ta|det\ta narcotic used as an analgesic and anaesthetic|attr\tan|det"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The most powerful opioid available for medical use.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did bbc.com report that the most powerful opioid available for medical use was released?",
                    "answer": "29/03/2016"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the most powerful opioid available for medical use?",
                    "score": 0.8987,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 29/03/2016 that The most powerful opioid available for medical use|ROOT\ton 29/03/2016|prep\tthat|mark\tThe|det\tmost|advmod\tmost powerful|amod\tthat The most powerful opioid available for medical use|dobj\tavailable for medical use|amod\tfor medical use|prep\tmedical|amod\tmedical use|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Its power and immediate effects are behind the addiction it generates.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did www.bbc.com report that its power and immediate effects were behind the addiction it generates?",
                    "answer": "29/03/2016"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What are the effects of addiction?",
                    "score": 0.8515,
                    "answers": "immediate|amod\timmediate effects|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the addiction it creates?",
                    "score": 0.8322,
                    "answers": "behind the addiction it generates|prep\tthe addiction it generates|pobj\tit generates|relcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between addiction and addiction?",
                    "score": 0.8004,
                    "answers": "on 29/03/2016|prep\tIts power and immediate effects|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Heroin, by comparison, provides a more durable but less immediate feeling, making it easier to treat by emergency medical services in case of overdose.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Heroin makes it easier to treat by what in case of overdose?",
                    "answer": "emergency medical services"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What does Heroin do to treat overdose cases?",
                    "score": 0.8929,
                    "answers": "in case of overdose|prep\tcase of overdose|pobj\tof overdose|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What emergency medical services are available to treat overdose deaths?",
                    "score": 0.8755,
                    "answers": "by emergency medical services|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the effects of Heroin on overdose?",
                    "score": 0.8519,
                    "answers": "to treat by emergency medical services in case of overdose|xcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Heroin?",
                    "score": 0.8451,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 29/03/2016 that Heroin , by comparison , provides a more durable but less immediate feeling , making it easier to treat by emergency medical services in case of overdose|ROOT\tHeroin|nsubj\tthat Heroin , by comparison , provides a more durable but less immediate feeling , making it easier to treat by emergency medical services in case of overdose|ccomp\tmaking it easier to treat by emergency medical services in case of overdose|advcl\tit easier to treat by emergency medical services in case of overdose|ccomp\toverdose|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the effect of Heroin on emergency medical services?",
                    "score": 0.8319,
                    "answers": "emergency|nmod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "That even means that many of those who died from overdose are found with the syringe in their arm.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What was found in the arm of many of the people who died from overdose?",
                    "answer": "the syringe"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many overdose deaths are reported each year?",
                    "score": 0.8501,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tThat|nsubj\tthat|mark\twho|nsubj\ttheir|poss"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many people die from overdose?",
                    "score": 0.8481,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 29/03/2016 that That even means that many of those who died from overdose are found with the syringe in their arm|ROOT\tthat That even means that many of those who died from overdose are found with the syringe in their arm|ccomp\twith the syringe in their arm|prep\tthe syringe in their arm|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Fentanyl is injected, but also applied in patches and taken in tablets.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What kind of tablets were used to take Fentanyl?",
                    "answer": "tablets"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What type of medication is Fentanyl used for?",
                    "score": 0.8851,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tis|auxpass\t,|punct\talso|advmod\tpatches|pobj\tand|cc"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of Fentanyl being taken in tablets?",
                    "score": 0.8096,
                    "answers": "but|cc"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Fentanyl?",
                    "score": 0.7991,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 29/03/2016 that Fentanyl is injected , but also applied in patches and taken in tablets|ROOT\ton 29/03/2016|prep\tFentanyl|nsubjpass\tthat Fentanyl is injected , but also applied in patches and taken in tablets|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The one that occurs in clandestine laboratories, unlike the pharmacist, is the one that is behind the most deaths, since it is mixed with heroin.",
            "question_answers": [],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What drugs are mixed with heroin?",
                    "score": 0.8908,
                    "answers": "with heroin|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is mixed with heroin in clandestine labs?",
                    "score": 0.86,
                    "answers": "since it is mixed with heroin|advcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many deaths occur in clandestine labs compared to the pharmacist?",
                    "score": 0.8468,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 29/03/2016 that The one that occurs in clandestine laboratories , unlike the pharmacist , is the one that is behind the most deaths , since it is mixed with heroin|ROOT\tthat occurs in clandestine laboratories , unlike the pharmacist ,|relcl\tin clandestine laboratories|prep\tclandestine|amod\tclandestine laboratories|pobj\tunlike the pharmacist|prep\tthe one that is behind the most deaths , since it is mixed with heroin|attr\tmost|amod\tsince|mark\theroin|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "It's even sold as a substitute because it's a very similar white powder and it's also similar to cocaine.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What kind of powder is it similar to?",
                    "answer": "white powder"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How similar is cocaine to cocaine?",
                    "score": 0.9047,
                    "answers": "it 's also similar to cocaine|conj\tsimilar to cocaine|acomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the similarities between white powder and cocaine?",
                    "score": 0.8661,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 29/03/2016 that It 's even sold as a substitute because it 's a very similar white powder and it 's also similar to cocaine|ROOT\ton 29/03/2016|prep\tthat|mark\tIt|nsubjpass\t's|auxpass\teven|advmod\tthat It 's even sold as a substitute because it 's a very similar white powder and it 's also similar to cocaine|ccomp\tas a substitute|prep\ta|det\ta substitute|pobj\tbecause|mark\tit|nsubj\tbecause it 's a very similar white powder and it 's also similar to cocaine|advcl\ta|det\tvery|advmod\tvery similar|amod\twhite|amod\ta very similar white powder|attr\tand|cc\tit|nsubj\talso|advmod\tto cocaine|prep\tcocaine|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "But fentanyl is much more potent.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What drug is more potent than fentanyl?",
                    "answer": "fentanyl"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How much more lethal is fentanyl than opiod?",
                    "score": 0.9127,
                    "answers": "much more|advmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How much more potent is fentanyl?",
                    "score": 0.9071,
                    "answers": "much|advmod\tmuch more potent|acomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the effects of fentanyl on humans?",
                    "score": 0.8996,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 29/03/2016 that But fentanyl is much more potent|ROOT\ton 29/03/2016|prep\tthat|mark\tBut|cc\tthat But fentanyl is much more potent|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Users, often without knowing what it is, consume it as heroin, so with the same amount it is much more lethal.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did bbc.com report that users often consume heroin as heroin?",
                    "answer": "29/03/2016"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How lethal is heroin?",
                    "score": 0.9113,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 29/03/2016 that Users , often without knowing what it is , consume it as heroin , so with the same amount it is much more lethal|ROOT\ton 29/03/2016|prep\tthat|mark\tUsers|nsubj\t,|punct\toften|advmod\twhat|attr\tit|nsubj\twhat it is|ccomp\t,|punct\tthat Users , often without knowing what it is , consume it as heroin , so with the same amount it is much more lethal|ccomp\tit|dobj\tas heroin|prep\theroin|pobj\t,|punct\tso|advmod\twith the same amount|prep\tthe|det\tsame|amod\tthe same amount|pobj\tit|nsubj\tso with the same amount it is much more lethal|advcl\tmuch|advmod\tmuch more|advmod\tmuch more lethal|acomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the use of heroin?",
                    "score": 0.8251,
                    "answers": "often without knowing what it is|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the difference between heroin and heroin?",
                    "score": 0.8212,
                    "answers": "knowing what it is|pcomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "In addition, mixing with cocaine and heroin further increases its effects, according to experts.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What two drugs did bbc.com report increased the effects of mixing with?",
                    "answer": "cocaine and heroin"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What are the effects of mixing cocaine and heroin?",
                    "score": 0.8533,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 29/03/2016 that In addition , mixing with cocaine and heroin further increases its effects , according to experts|ROOT\ton 29/03/2016|prep\tthat|mark\tIn addition|prep\taddition|pobj\t,|punct\tmixing with cocaine and heroin|csubj\twith cocaine and heroin|prep\tcocaine and heroin|pobj\tand|cc\theroin|conj\tfurther|advmod\tthat In addition , mixing with cocaine and heroin further increases its effects , according to experts|ccomp\tits|poss\tits effects|dobj\t,|punct\taccording to experts|prep\tto experts|prep\texperts|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "On the street it receives other names, such as'China White'.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did www.bbc.com report that on the street it receives other names such as 'China White'?",
                    "answer": "29/03/2016"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What other names does China White get?",
                    "score": 0.7926,
                    "answers": "other names , such as'China White '|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is China White?",
                    "score": 0.7086,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\ton 29/03/2016|prep\tsuch|amod\tsuch as'China|compound\tsuch as'China White '|appos"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Where does it come from?The DEA says that fentanyl comes mainly from Mexico, where the authorities have dismantled several laboratories.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What does the DEA say comes from Mexico?",
                    "answer": "fentanyl"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Where does fentanyl originate from?",
                    "score": 0.8617,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\ton 29/03/2016|prep\tDEA says that fentanyl comes mainly from Mexico , where the authorities have dismantled several laboratories|ROOT\tthat fentanyl comes mainly from Mexico , where the authorities have dismantled several laboratories|ccomp\tmainly from Mexico , where the authorities have dismantled several laboratories|prep\tMexico , where the authorities have dismantled several laboratories|pobj\tthe|det\twhere the authorities have dismantled several laboratories|relcl\tseveral|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Where does fentanyl come from?",
                    "score": 0.847,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 29/03/2016 that Where does it come from?The|ROOT\tthat|mark\tWhere|pobj\tdoes|aux\tit|nsubj\tthat Where does it come|ccomp\tfrom?The|punct\tthat|mark\tfentanyl|nsubj\tmainly|advmod\t,|punct\twhere|advmod\tthe authorities|nsubj\thave|aux"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Where did the drugs originate from?",
                    "score": 0.8285,
                    "answers": "several laboratories|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Although the threat is increasing, fentanyl is not a new drug.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What drug is not a new drug?",
                    "answer": "fentanyl"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Is fentanyl a new drug?",
                    "score": 0.9102,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 29/03/2016 that Although the threat is increasing , fentanyl is not a new drug|ROOT\tis|aux\tthat Although the threat is increasing , fentanyl is not a new drug|ccomp\tnot|neg\ta|det\tnew|amod\ta new drug|attr"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the current threat of fentanyl?",
                    "score": 0.8514,
                    "answers": "on 29/03/2016|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the threat of fentanyl?",
                    "score": 0.8478,
                    "answers": "Although|mark\tthe|det\tthe threat|nsubj\tAlthough the threat is increasing|advcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of fentanyl being a new drug?",
                    "score": 0.8412,
                    "answers": "that|mark\t,|punct"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Already between  and , more than  deaths were attributed to the drug, many of them in cities such as Chicago, Detroit and Philadelphia.",
            "question_answers": [],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many deaths were attributed to heroin in the US in 2015?",
                    "score": 0.8398,
                    "answers": "Chicago , Detroit and Philadelphia|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The substances related to these deaths were tracked and DEA reached a laboratory in Mexico.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reached a laboratory in Mexico City?",
                    "answer": "DEA"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Did the DEA track the substances related to the deaths?",
                    "score": 0.8598,
                    "answers": "that The substances related to these deaths were tracked and DEA reached a laboratory in Mexico|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many deaths were linked to the DEA?",
                    "score": 0.8263,
                    "answers": "these deaths|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Where was the DEA lab located in Mexico in 2016?",
                    "score": 0.7587,
                    "answers": "a laboratory in Mexico|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the name of the lab where the drugs were collected?",
                    "score": 0.7171,
                    "answers": "on 29/03/2016|prep\tThe substances related to these deaths|nsubjpass"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "When it was dismantled, the substance almost disappeared from the market.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "On what date did bbc.com report that the substance almost disappeared from the market when it was dismantled?",
                    "answer": "29/03/2016"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Where did the substance disappear from the market?",
                    "score": 0.8454,
                    "answers": "from the market|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the substance that disappeared from the market after it was dismantled?",
                    "score": 0.7765,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tit|nsubjpass\tWhen it was dismantled|advcl"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "According to U.S. authorities, the drug produced in Mexico crosses the southwestern border and reaches California and Arizona, from where it is redistributed to the main heroin markets, especially on the east coast.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "On what coast of the US is heroin most commonly found?",
                    "answer": "east coast"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Where does the drug produced in Mexico cross the southwestern border?",
                    "score": 0.8462,
                    "answers": "the southwestern border|dobj\tfrom where|prep\tthe east coast|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the amount of heroin that is produced in Mexico?",
                    "score": 0.8234,
                    "answers": "to the main heroin markets , especially on the east coast|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the main heroin market on the east coast?",
                    "score": 0.8119,
                    "answers": "the main heroin markets , especially on the east coast|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Cartels such as Sinaloa, according to what emerges from DEA research, add doses of fentanyl or derivatives to Mexican heroin, resulting in increased addiction and more likely overdose.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What drug does Sinaloa add to heroin?",
                    "answer": "fentanyl"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What drugs are added to Mexican heroin?",
                    "score": 0.9097,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\taccording to what emerges from DEA research|prep\tof fentanyl or derivatives|prep\tto Mexican heroin|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What drugs add to Mexican heroin?",
                    "score": 0.9071,
                    "answers": "on 29/03/2016|prep\tthat|mark\tsuch|amod\t,|punct\twhat|nsubj\t,|punct\tor|cc\tMexican heroin|pobj\t,|punct\tand|cc\tmore|advmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between fentanyl and Mexican heroin?",
                    "score": 0.8528,
                    "answers": "resulting in increased addiction and more likely overdose|advcl\tin increased addiction and more likely overdose|prep\tincreased addiction and more likely overdose|pobj\tmore likely overdose|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Sinaloa?",
                    "score": 0.7584,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 29/03/2016 that Cartels such as Sinaloa , according to what emerges from DEA research , add doses of fentanyl or derivatives to Mexican heroin , resulting in increased addiction and more likely overdose|ROOT\tCartels such as Sinaloa|nsubj\tsuch as Sinaloa|prep\tto what emerges from DEA research|prep\twhat emerges from DEA research|pcomp\tfrom DEA research|prep\tDEA research|pobj\tthat Cartels such as Sinaloa , according to what emerges from DEA research , add doses of fentanyl or derivatives to Mexican heroin , resulting in increased addiction and more likely overdose|ccomp\tdoses of fentanyl or derivatives|dobj\tfentanyl or derivatives|pobj\tderivatives|conj\tincreased|amod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Its use is part of the so-called 'epidemic 'of heroin and opiate use throughout the country.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the term used to describe the use of heroin and opiate throughout the country?",
                    "answer": "'epidemic"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the use of opiate and heroin?",
                    "score": 0.8908,
                    "answers": "heroin and opiate|nmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is opiate use?",
                    "score": 0.8875,
                    "answers": "opiate|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the epidemic of heroin and opiate use?",
                    "score": 0.8846,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 29/03/2016 that Its use is part of the so - called ' epidemic ' of heroin and opiate use throughout the country|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the heroin and opiate use throughout the country?",
                    "score": 0.8733,
                    "answers": "of heroin and opiate use throughout the country|prep\theroin and opiate use throughout the country|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "It's not just about fentanyl anymore, it's about its derivatives.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the drug that bbc reported on 29/03/2016?",
                    "answer": "fentanyl"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What are the derivatives of fentanyl?",
                    "score": 0.8613,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\twww.bbc.com reported on 29/03/2016 that It 's not just about fentanyl anymore , it 's about its derivatives|ROOT\ton 29/03/2016|prep\tthat|mark\tIt|nsubj\tIt 's not just about fentanyl anymore|ccomp\tnot|neg\tjust|advmod\tabout fentanyl|prep\tfentanyl|pobj\tanymore|advmod\t,|punct\tit|nsubj\tthat It 's not just about fentanyl anymore , it 's about its derivatives|ccomp\tabout its derivatives|prep\tits|poss\tits derivatives|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The current outbreak is much wider geographically and involves a greater typology of people, according to the authorities.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did www.bbc.com report on 29/03/2016",
                    "answer": "The current outbreak is much wider geographically and involves a greater typology of people,"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What type of typology does the current outbreak involve?",
                    "score": 0.8354,
                    "answers": "a|det\tgreater|amod\tof people|prep\tpeople|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the current outbreak of the flu?",
                    "score": 0.8306,
                    "answers": "on 29/03/2016|prep\tthat|mark\tThe|det\tcurrent|amod\tmuch|advmod\tand|cc\tinvolves a greater typology of people , according to the authorities|conj\t,|punct\tthe|det\tthe authorities|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many typology people are in the current outbreak?",
                    "score": 0.7892,
                    "answers": "according to the authorities|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the spread of the current outbreak?",
                    "score": 0.7675,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 29/03/2016 that The current outbreak is much wider geographically and involves a greater typology of people , according to the authorities|ROOT\tthat The current outbreak is much wider geographically and involves a greater typology of people , according to the authorities|ccomp\tmuch wider geographically|acomp\tgeographically|advmod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "According to an intermediary quoted by The New York Times, ten grams of fentanyl cost USUSD and are sold to the final consumer for USUSD, allowing them to earn USUSD per week.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How many grams of fentanyl cost USUSD?",
                    "answer": "ten grams"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How much money does fentanyl allow people to earn per week?",
                    "score": 0.7624,
                    "answers": "allowing them to earn USUSD per week|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the benefits of buying ten grams of fentanyl?",
                    "score": 0.7508,
                    "answers": "are sold to the final consumer for USUSD , allowing them to earn USUSD per week|conj\tthem to earn USUSD per week|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the dollar amount of fentanyl being sold for?",
                    "score": 0.73,
                    "answers": "According to an intermediary quoted by The New York Times|prep\tfentanyl|pobj\tfor USUSD|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the average price of fentanyl per week?",
                    "score": 0.7123,
                    "answers": "USUSD per week|dobj\tper week|prep\tweek|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How much is the final consumer for the US Dollar?",
                    "score": 0.6918,
                    "answers": "final|amod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "'It is cheaper and the effect is better ', one consumer told New York newspaper.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did bbc.com report on 29/03/2016?",
                    "answer": "'It is cheaper and the effect is better"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the cost of the New York newspaper?",
                    "score": 0.8245,
                    "answers": "cheaper|acomp\tone consumer|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the average cost of a gallon of milk in New York?",
                    "score": 0.8014,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 29/03/2016|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the effect of the website \"bbc.com\"?",
                    "score": 0.7118,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 29/03/2016 that ' It is cheaper and the effect is better ' , one consumer told New York newspaper|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the effect ofbbc.com?",
                    "score": 0.6037,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "'It's the best I've ever taken ', another told Macleans magazine in Canada, where also the use of this drug and its consequences are on the rise.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What did bbc.com report on the drug on 29/03/2016?",
                    "answer": "'It's the best I've ever taken"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What are the consequences of using opiod?",
                    "score": 0.7783,
                    "answers": "where also the use of this drug and its consequences are on the rise|relcl"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the use of this drug in Canada?",
                    "score": 0.7608,
                    "answers": "this drug|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Another factor to take into account is addiction to legal opiates.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is another factor to take into account?",
                    "answer": "addiction to legal opiates"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the addiction to legal opiates?",
                    "score": 0.8984,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 29/03/2016 that Another factor to take into account is addiction to legal opiates|ROOT\ton 29/03/2016|prep\tthat|mark\tAnother|det\tAnother factor to take into account|nsubj\tto|aux\tto take into account|relcl\tinto account|prep\taccount|pobj\tthat Another factor to take into account is addiction to legal opiates|ccomp\taddiction to legal opiates|attr\tto legal opiates|prep\tlegal opiates|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the definition of legal opiates?",
                    "score": 0.8716,
                    "answers": "legal|amod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "According to the U.S. Centers for Disease Control (CDC), people die in the U.S. USA.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What does CDC stand for?",
                    "answer": "U.S. Centers for Disease Control"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many people die annually from the CDC?",
                    "score": 0.8388,
                    "answers": "for Disease Control|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the CDC's definition of death rate?",
                    "score": 0.7838,
                    "answers": "According to the U.S. Centers for Disease Control ( CDC )|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the CDC?",
                    "score": 0.7272,
                    "answers": "to the U.S. Centers for Disease Control ( CDC )|prep\tthe U.S. Centers for Disease Control ( CDC )|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "every day for an overdose of painkillers prescribed by doctors.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is prescribed by doctors every day?",
                    "answer": "painkillers"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many opiods are prescribed by doctors per day?",
                    "score": 0.7796,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 29/03/2016 that every day for an overdose of painkillers prescribed by doctors|ROOT\ton 29/03/2016|prep\tthat|mark\tevery|det\tthat every day|ccomp\tfor an overdose of painkillers prescribed by doctors|dep\tan|det\tan overdose of painkillers prescribed by doctors|pobj\tof painkillers|prep\tpainkillers|pobj\tprescribed by doctors|acl\tby doctors|agent\tdoctors|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "In , millions of opium-derived recipes were made in the country .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When were millions of opium-derived recipes made in the country?",
                    "answer": "In"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many opium derived recipes were made in the country in 2016?",
                    "score": 0.8514,
                    "answers": "millions of opium - derived recipes|nsubjpass"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "How to stop it? 'Fentanyl will remain a threat as long as current clandestine production continues ', says the DEA in its report on drugs of .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "How long does the DEA say 'Fentanyl will remain a threat'?",
                    "answer": "clandestine production continues"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How long does the DEA say 'Fentanyl will remain a threat'?",
                    "answer": "current clandestine production continues"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What does the DEA say about Fentanyl?",
                    "score": 0.8791,
                    "answers": "a threat|attr\t' Fentanyl will remain a threat as long as current clandestine production continues ' , says the DEA in its report on drugs of|ROOT\ton drugs of|prep\tdrugs of|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What will happen to Fentanyl if it continues to be a threat?",
                    "score": 0.8469,
                    "answers": "Fentanyl will remain a threat as long as current clandestine production continues|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the DEA's stance on Fentanyl?",
                    "score": 0.8335,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com|nsubj\ton 29/03/2016|prep\tthat|mark\tHow|advmod\tto|aux\tthat How to stop it|ccomp\tit|dobj\t?|punct\t'|punct\twill|aux\ta|det\tas|advmod\tas long as current clandestine production continues|advmod\tas|mark\tcurrent|amod\tclandestine|amod\tcurrent clandestine production|nsubj\tas current clandestine production continues|advcl\t'|punct\t,|punct\tthe|det\tthe DEA|nsubj\tits|poss\tof|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Fentanyl?",
                    "score": 0.8264,
                    "answers": "www.bbc.com reported on 29/03/2016 that How to stop it ?|ROOT\tFentanyl|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Experts believe that the lack of experience of clandestine laboratories that have joined the production of fentanyl is behind many deaths.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the cause of many deaths?",
                    "answer": "the lack of experience of clandestine laboratories that have joined the production of fentanyl"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many deaths were caused by the production of fentanyl?",
                    "score": 0.8361,
                    "answers": "that Experts believe that the lack of experience of clandestine laboratories that have joined the production of fentanyl is behind many deaths|ccomp\tof experience of clandestine laboratories that have joined the production of fentanyl|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "These laboratories are the first to be interested in ensuring that their product does not lead to further deaths.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 29/03/2016 that these laboratories were the first to be interested in ensuring that their product does not lead to further deaths?",
                    "answer": "www.bbc.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What are the safety standards for testing products in labs?",
                    "score": 0.8437,
                    "answers": "to further deaths|prep\tfurther deaths|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the purpose of these laboratories?",
                    "score": 0.7536,
                    "answers": "These|det\tThese laboratories|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is the first to be interested in ensuring that their product doesn't lead to further deaths?",
                    "score": 0.7327,
                    "answers": "the first to be interested in ensuring that their product does not lead to further deaths|attr"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "For the DEA, the danger, they insist, is that consumers don't know that they're taking it.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 29/03/2016 that for the DEA, the danger, they insist, is that consumers don't know that they're taking it?",
                    "answer": "www.bbc.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the DEA doing with the DEA?",
                    "score": 0.6893,
                    "answers": "that consumers do n't know that they 're taking it|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between the DEA and consumers?",
                    "score": 0.6434,
                    "answers": "consumers|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the danger of the DEA?",
                    "score": 0.6375,
                    "answers": "the danger|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "'It will be consumed mostly unconsciously mixed with heroin and other drugs ', alerts the DEA.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Along with what other drugs was bbc.com reporting that it would be consumed mostly unconsciously?",
                    "answer": "heroin and other drugs"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What drugs are being mixed with heroin and other drugs?",
                    "score": 0.8488,
                    "answers": "with heroin and other drugs|prep\theroin and other drugs|pobj\tother|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does the DEA do with drugs?",
                    "score": 0.8284,
                    "answers": "the DEA|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}